# Łukasz Rymko

## Curriculum Vitae



#### Personal data:

Living in Gdańsk, Poland Birth: 8th January 1989 ☎ +48 661 489 887 ☒ lukasz@rymko.pl ☒ lurym89@gmail.com

### Computer skills:

Languages: Go, Python, Java, Node.JS, C++, C#
OSes: Linux, Windows
Others: vim, git, Post-greSQL, LATEX

#### Languages:

Polish: Native English: Proficient Russian: Communicative I am a passionate engineer. I like to solve problems and build things. My interests are centred around building scalable web services. I am responsible for creating backend solutions that are secure, scalable and work reliably. I personally believe that you need to use right tool for the job so I like to switch between various languages and technologies. In my previous profesional experience I used to write code in Golang, Python, Java, Node.JS and C#. In the last two years I focused my personal interests around Golang because I believe it is suitable for most backend projects and will become more and more popular in the future. While creating backend services I learned a lot about automating infrastructure management, continuous integration and delivery. I can jump into Ansible and Terraform scripts without any delay. I am mostly experienced with Amazon AWS, but Google Cloud is not new to me. In my spare time I build things with my RaspberryPls or Arduino and occasionally write code that just solves my day-to-day problems.

## **Experience**

#### Backend developer, FindHotel.net, Remote

since 08.2017

I am responsible for creating low latency, scalable Golang backend service. My project aggregates information about prices and availabilty for all hotels around the world. It needs to be resilient to unreliable sources of information and optimize for the best user experience.

### Backend developer, FoxCommerce, Remote

05.2017 - 07.2017

Project was about delivering best eCommerce experience to the customers. I was responsible for developing and maintaining backend services for eCommerce platform using technologies like Kafka, Consul, Docker and ElasticSearch. I used Go as my main language there.

Backend developer and Design Lead, Intel Corporation, 04.2012 - 04.2017 Gdańsk

I was a technical lead developer of team that is responsible for creating backend cloud services based on hardware root of trust that are supporting unique position of Intel products on the market. My duties were mostly related to security and cryptography topics but I had to have in mind scalability and performance also. My goal was to make our team easy to work with and provide productive, agile atmosphere.

**Software Development Intern**, *Intel Corporation*, Gdańsk

10.2010 - 04.2012

Java Software Developer, Nethos, Gdańsk

01.2009 - 10.2009

Creating various B2E applications using Java SE, Java EE with Echo2 framework.

# **Public repositories**

**Tricity bus**, https://github.com/lurym/tricity\_bus

Node.JS

Going to work is tough sometimes. This project aggregates data from public transportation webpage and show current buses next to my home and work.

**Temperature sensor**, https://github.com/lurym/temperature\_ **Python** sensor

This is a simple program that sends temperature sensors data to ThingSpeak backend service. I am using it at home for temperature monitoring.

Flashcards, https://bitbucket.org/lurym/fiszki

**MTFX** 

This project is used to simplify creating two-sided flashcards (called fiszki in polish language) using LaTeX. My SO needed to create flashcards for her students but did not know LaTeX, so I created that project to simplify her work.

**Vending machine**, https://github.com/lurym/vending\_machine **Go**Simple restful service that shows possible REST API for Vending Machine (written in Golang). It was done as a recruitment exercise for one of the companies.

#### **Education**

**Informatics**, *Gdańsk University of Technology*, *Master of Science* **2011 – 2012** Second cycle studies on the Faculty of Electronics, Telecommunications and Informatics.

Mathematics, Gdańsk University of Technology

2009 - 2010

First cycle studies on the Faculty of Technical Physics and Applied Mathematics. Resignation at will.

Informatics, Gdańsk University of Technology, Engineer

2007 - 2011

First cycle studies on the Faculty of Electronics, Telecommunications and Informatics.

## Master thesis

Title: Evaluation of Feature Selection methods for Text Classification

Supervisor: Julian Szymański, PhD MEng

**Description**: This work describes five approaches used for text features selection aiming at reducing the dimensionality of the vector space model. Methods are evaluated through classification task performed on the experimental high dimensional datasets created from Wikipedia articles database. Results of classification quality have been provided for all of the methods. The best one has been used for evaluation of selection and classification scalability. My thesis article was published in Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNCS) book: https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-642-38610-7\_44